# Claude V. Aldric

# Software Engineer

#### **PROJECTS (CURATED)**

## COVID-19 Dashboard (link)

A responsive COVID-19 dashboard featuring a U.S. choropleth timeline map of confirmed cases and an SIR mathematical model and fit. Built using HTML/CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, Python, and an external API; deployed on GitHub pages.

# Battleship (Game Clone) (<u>link</u>)

A clone of the Battleship strategy game built with two other collaborators using the Mongo/Express/React/Node stack, Bootstrap, and Heroku. Our team adopted Agile Scrum with Jira where I served as the Product Owner and Lead Developer.

# **Client Data Template Parser** | *StepStone Group*

A script that automates the hourly collection and aggregation of relevant financial data from 600+ data templates scattered throughout the shared file system. Built using Python, MySQL, Task Scheduler, and Git/GitHub.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

# **StepStone Group** | *La Jolla, CA & Cleveland, OH*

## Senior Analyst

JANUARY 2020 - MAY 2020 | 5 MOS

Created software solutions and spearheaded 6 data analytics and workflow automation projects/initiatives, saving 350+ hours per quarter.

Appointed to an innovation task force that leveraged research and technology to maximize department workflow efficiency and data analytics capabilities.

Contributed to multiple Excel and Power BI data dashboards through data wrangling, KPI calculation creation and implementation, and data visualization.

## Analyst

APRIL 2018 - JANUARY 2020 | 1 YR 10 MOS

Overhauled the manual financial reporting through a "one-click" report template using Power Query, DAX, MySQL, and VBA, saving 300+ hours per quarter.

Automated the cash flow process using Excel and VBA, which generates the dynamic cover letter and the complete Outlook email to be sent to GPs.

Served the clients' quarterly and ad-hoc financial reporting needs.

Mentored and directed interns and junior analysts.

## **Courtland Partners** | Cleveland, OH

#### Analyst

SEPTEMBER 2015 - APRIL 2018 | 2 YRS 8 MOS

Took over and streamlined the document management process, effectively managing 4,000+ financial documents per quarter.

Automated various Excel workflows using VBA, saving 10+ hours per quarter.

Produced quarterly and ad-hoc client performance and cash reconciliation reports.

#### **CONTACT/LINKS**

<u>claude@aldric.dev</u>

aldric.dev

linkedin.com/in/caldric/

github.com/caldric

#### **SKILLS**

TypeScript, Python, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, SQL

React.js, Redux, Express.js, Node.js, jQuery, Bootstrap MongoDB, MySQL, PostgreSQL Agile, Scrum (Jira), Kanban Git/GitHub, CLI, Linux, Vim Amazon Web Services (AWS),

#### **EDUCATION**

Heroku

Software Engineering General Assembly 12-week, 420+ hour software engineering program (coding bootcamp)

BS in Math, Statistics Minor Cleveland State University Awards: 4.0/4.0 GPA, Summa Cum Laude, Valedictorian Candidate, Outstanding Senior, Outstanding Mathematics Major, Honors Program, Choose Ohio First Research Cohort and Scholarship, President's List, Dean's List

Associate in Financial Services Lorain County Community College Awards: 3.9/4.0 GPA, Graduated with Honors, Dean's List